the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet will exam of
holography
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frank de Freitas
and welcome to another week of holotalk
we actually have two guests this week we
have Rob Taylor from fourth dimension
holographics in Nashville Indiana and we
have Mikhail greaching I think that's
how you pronounce the last name my
apologies if it's pronounced incorrectly
it's spelled g-r-i-c-h-i-n-e and Mikhail
is the director of the giola lab in
Lithuania and both will be on to tell us
about the first totally automated
holographic pulse camera system from
giola that's being installed here in the
United States so we will have them on in
just a minute but first I have a few
announcements to make first of which
is happy birthday to my daughter who's
going to be 20 years old on November 2nd
and she is a physics and Mathematics
major whose Professor was in one of my
holography workshops back in the early
80s so I just want to say happy birthday
to you and uh it did the odds and
strange feeling to finally have a
daughter or child
that's in their 20s now so what does
that say about me she's the oldest of
three and happy birthday
got an email from TJ Dr Jay Ong from
Lake Forest College and he wanted to
inform me that he now has a holography
kit that he put together and is
available for sale at his integraff
website which is based around
laser pointer or laser diode holography
and it comes with the laser diode the
film the chemistry and I believe one or
two instruction manuals on how to do
experiments using the kit so if you have
an interest in purchasing the kit you
can go to the link page and the link
that you're looking for is integrath
click on that link and it will take you
to TJ's website and you can get more
information and ordering information on
this kit
also I'd like to remind everyone that
this Wednesday evening
is the open house here in the studio at
Allentown Pennsylvania and the topic
is post not actually pulse but the
holographic portraits and it ties in
very nicely with the show that we're
having this week and when you come into
the studio you'll be able to see
examples of pulse telegraphy and also a
few Holograms that were shot when myself
and my youngest daughter went to New
York to the Sony Center to have our
holographic portraits done on Sony's
instant stereographic holographic camera
as well so we'll have them here and to
close out the evening we'll be showing
you how you can do your own little
holographic portraits using your typical
equipment that you have in your studio
such as your sand table your continuous
wave helium these neon or
diode laser system but what's
interesting is you can shoot these
Holograms starting with your 35
millimeter camera in any standard 35
millimeter Cameron and proceed to make
your holographic portrait and we'll take
a look at both the holographic strip
Masters the laser transmission Masters
and also the transfers now of course
these Holograms are nothing compared to
the um laser systems that are out there
in some of the Laboratories but it makes
very nice little holographic portraits
that you could do on your own of your
friends and family and pets or whatever
and you might want to come out and check
that out it starts at 7 30 p.m promptly
London about an hour and a half to nine
o'clock it's free of charge but you do
need to send me an email or give me a
call on the phone to let me know to
expect you to be here there's
refreshment Surge and we all have a
pretty good time so let's move on to our
interview and I just want to thank you
for tuning in we're having a great
season this is the third season here
Hall of talk and we're getting a lot of
listeners this year
each week I like to think that I'm able
to bring you news and information
concerning the fields of lasers and
holography I hope you enjoy the show I
try to have guests each week but
occasionally I'll take a show on my own
in case you know sometimes someone can't
make it as scheduled or just that there
happens to be
I'd like to pass along to you such as a
special show that I have coming up on
the re-emergence of single beam
holography which should be very
interesting for a lot of amateurs and
hobbyists out there to hear how you can
do some very nice single beam Holograms
including image plane transfers and
things of that nature that'll be coming
up as well so I will say thank you for
tuning in I'm not going to come on after
the show's over and I hope you tune in
each and every week to hold a talk
throughout this season which will run to
Memorial Day
the year 2000 so thanks for tuning in
here's the show see you next week
Frank well hello how did you know it was
me oh yeah because uh this line doesn't
get much use now we just uh activated
this line for the studio oh I see well
you're getting to have a lot of fun out
there yeah we sure are I can't hardly
stand it I'm so excited around right now
why don't we start right off by you
telling everyone what it is that you're
doing out there well we have uh just
installed and uh completed the first
master and copying uh with the
I guess you could say it's this
hemisphere's first totally automated
holographic pulse camera system and we
have been installing it since last
Thursday
and today we just started doing the
calibration and testing with the test
slavich plates and we just just stuck
the 30 by 40 centimeter
H2 transfer reflection copy on the
drying rack about 10 minutes ago we did
my I just recorded my father who's 72
years old and he was my first test
subject well you know I've only said
that there are so many people in our
history right now that really need to be
recorded holographically yeah it's uh
especially I I see uh big applications
for the very young and the very old
because you can record Young
children at the precious you know moment
when they're you know at a certain age
and they are really uh you know you
always want to remember them a certain
age and then uh you know older people
that have developed you know have a lot
of wisdom and that type of thing for uh
you know in the in their later years
they have a lot of character built into
their face it's a perfect time to record
that person yeah very interesting
three-dimensional subjects yeah yeah and
it's amazing for kids who have had
holographic portraits done that after 5
10 15 years have gone by and they go
back and they look at themselves again
looking at themselves as kids
you know staring back at themselves and
that's that's an incredible feeling yeah
it would be interesting to do and I
don't know that anybody's ever done it
but it would be interesting to a child
um masters of a child through you know
certain phases or ages of their life and
then incorporate those Masters in what
to like say a three-channel reflection
hologram so that you could actually see
them from a young age and then a little
bit older like say four or five years
older and then say four or five years
older again that would be an interesting
uh hologram that's a great idea that's a
great idea would it be too early for me
to ask you the price of this service
um no I think that we are going to be
doing uh 30 by 40 centimeter glass
pillai reflection copies for 495 dollars
that's our targeted price and I don't
see any reason why through this uh just
uh initial testing that we just
completed that we can't stay on target
with that price
very reasonable yeah that's pretty much
a price breakthrough yeah yeah
now why don't you tell everybody where
your studio is located and you also have
a retail shop and everything there don't
you yeah we're in a little town uh in
Southern Indiana called Nashville
Indiana we're kind of in the heart of
the Hoosier National Forest uh very uh
picturesque and rustic area down here in
Southern Indiana
um
it's a kind of a tourist town with a lot
of crafts people that make their own
products and so we like to think of
ourselves as a crafts people here too
now that we're uh have this pulse
photography system and we can be doing
recording is that a yes that's a solid
state laser in that system right
um yes yeah it's uh neodymium Yelp glass
phosphate laser driven by a crystal I
see and Flash lamps actually we got the
unless the components last Thursday and
unfortunately through the shipping from
Lithuania we experienced one flash lamp
that had broken and in the main
amplifier so we have been waiting for
about two or three days to get that in
and we just got that in last night at
five o'clock so we installed that last
night and we're up and running this
morning what's the power requirements
[Applause]
um we're using 220 or 240 volts but uh
it's a single phase and you can you
could you can power this thing actually
over a standard 110 current no kidding
yes wow yeah it's a it's a pretty uh
exciting thing to be involved in I'm
very very excited and lucky to be able
to have this is that relatively new this
technology or has it been around for
many years
coralsely applied to the system
it's a it's a relatively new technology
I would think uh you know I um I I would
probably like to refer you to uh Mikhail
because he's actually the inventor of
the camera system or most of the
components within
um he
works with giola the company that
actually manufactures this camera system
in Lithuania we actually
formed a partnership to get this into
the United States and use components
both from the US and Lithuania and
russian-based technology so we kind of
formed a combination to actually get the
required Parts together and actually
assemble a camera system here
easy to get to your shop from any or
could you name some of the larger
metropolitan areas that are around you
yeah we're about
um uh hour South of Indianapolis which
is the capital of Indiana
Cincinnati
Columbus Chicago Louisville Kentucky all
those are within easily driving distance
of you know say one to two hours oh
really yeah we're we're kind of
centrally located in between those areas
and I would imagine for a pulse portrait
something that's special that it
wouldn't be Beyond anyone to make a day
trip an overnight trip out of it no no
stay somewhere and have that done during
the day sightsee and that's our feeling
because we we plan on making this a
same-day service even with this totally
being a totally automated system we've
uh we can go from mastering to copying
mode
um
well you know basically with the flick
of a switch in about less than 30
seconds oh my goodness
um we plan on you know doing sittings in
the morning and then people can shop
within the 200 plus little shops within
Nashville and have a nice meal or
something come back view their master
and then we'll process the copy out and
dry it and should have the reflection
copied by you know that evening
now you say you have my film okay
um yeah he's here and uh he can tell you
more about this uh camera system and the
technology behind it uh I'm going to
have a link up to your website for the
show and right so your phone number
great and um like I said I'm really
excited I'll let you talk to him I'm
going to go and see if my dad's plate is
driving reflection copy I know that
feeling hey it's nice talking to you
okay bye-bye hello hello
this is Frankie Freitas oh yeah we do a
radio show here called whole talk yeah
yeah I know yeah you know okay I have a
couple questions I'd like to ask you all
right and first off maybe we should uh
just take a few minutes to speak about
giola if you could tell us a little bit
about the company uh yeah
um 1994
as a sister company of Australian
Hardware graphics holography
it's located in Adelaide South Australia
and this company specialized in large
format display photography I see using
tradition traditional lasers
[Music]
yeah
for
Holograms were really exciting it was up
to one by three meters rainbow kilograms
and up to one by one meter reflection oh
that'd be pretty big yeah yeah yeah I
don't even think I've ever well maybe I
have did they ever have any work it was
in images and time and space or any of
those other exhibits that went around
you know
really I don't know exactly I know
there's a lot of
uh
[Music]
you know growing of our company and
they'll tell about our product which is
which we have now okay I think so that
they can go to the website on the web
page yeah uh
it's a question about the result for our
website or yeah I'll put a link to your
website so people can go there and see
about giola
yeah.com
what about the holographic portrait
system can you tell us a little bit
about that in its operation about our
portrait camera yeah yeah yeah okay okay
I'll begin with a little from history
okay because this technique actually of
uh started and
in our company in 1996 in middle of 1996
and the geological about some research
work in order to record
final programs
I quote this was a solid state
and the first experiments were pretty
successful and the same time
due to the technology of
color control for reflection how
everyone was introduced and so those two
things actually were basis of our future
design
and then we exhibited high quality
reflection programs for 40 by 60
centimeters
printed with this technique a completely
powerful technique in laser 9700 in
Munich and then one month later we
exhibited them in the International
Symposium for display photography okay
in Lake Forest in the UC and stuff yet
after that angel actually become
separate from us from Australian
holographic and our company doing
business
is a
most advanced pulse Technology For This
by holography
regarding our
um
uh present product
our traditional field of activity is a
High large format holography and all
flavors
and the photo of a range of high energy
lasers based on medium yield and edema
and phospheric glass system
and recently we completed design of
range of laser for General scientific
applications
uh
of course we produce Holograms itself so
currently Factor one by one meter size
both reflection and rainbows what's the
largest size that the camera will
produce
um this camera can produce 60 by 40 and
that's with our standard size yeah
that's nice but there is no restriction
in laser energy
at least for say 60 by 80 centimeters
it's possible to to build such a camera
yeah and uh yeah is this the first unit
in the United States
yeah that's true and they have to say
that so first that's the first what
about the slavage recording materials
now you're a distributor for those right
or here
in photography community
and uh you know after accurate
discontinued production of holographic
materials uh this emotion from flourish
uh slowly but surely by this Market
and vipm
uh uh from grain material for
phd014 web
uh recording and the PM his green
sensitive material yeah and the other
one it works fine for reflection
holography as well doesn't it yeah both
both yeah and they're pretty similar to
access the respectively uh
he75 HD and he 56 HD yeah the year one
is not the O3 uh
zero one yeah
it's the next family
left
um
is what sensitive and phd060 is with a
pancromatic response
do both the zero one and the zero three
require late tensification in the
processor
um not really not really you know with
authentication I can explain actually um
both work required for intensification
if you know one records just with A
continuous program it's not necessary to
use identification at all okay
there's a lot of question about that
especially with people that are dealing
with the holography as a hobby yeah
there's a lot of questions about this
late tensification yeah usually of
course the years
some of these guys you know have these
labs in their house yeah with five
milliwatt 10 milliwatt-hini lasers and
they're shooting four by five inch
plates or film and they're wondering you
know do they have to do this late
tensification or
notification brings the sensitivity of
holographic plays
which is usually less maybe several
times less than
um
sensitivity for continuous wave
radiation so this process brings this
sensitivity approximately to the same
level yes at equalizer and that is like
really useful for uh pulse work any
other information you can give us about
the camera do you expect to have any
more installations here in the states
um no now we are building a camera for
Germany for some medical application I
don't know exactly from face surgery and
um and we have
several other possible uh contracts
not better
when it's still in progress and so I
cannot give more details about this
would it be okay if I asked you what the
price of one of these systems runs if
someone wanted to contact you to get one
of these systems what's the price of one
of these systems well actually depends
on uh you know on Final requirements
five and my textures from around a
hundred thousand hundred thousand
dollars so really serious technique and
quite complicated you know machine and
you know
cannot be too cheap yeah yeah
and what's what's the Lifetime on the uh
on the laser usually and as long as the
flash lamp lasts I would imagine I mean
just the rod Excel itself have to ever
be replaced or just the flashlight
requires replacement number once a year
and in the amplifier
we never replaced the first one to now
amplifiers I suppose
really lost for forever then it requires
some maintenance maybe once it two
months you know one can clean some
Optics inside and stuff like that
um it doesn't run off of batteries
either does it
um just a joke
we've been working with a lot of these
little diodes that we can use little
batteries on so this is a whole nother
ball game for everybody
I think it might even I don't know maybe
turning us down or similar to all of the
system you know they fit it in the size
of I don't know maybe a fax machine yeah
but it sounds like a wonderful system
just the way that it is right now it
sounds like a wonderful system I mean
it's it seems awful simple just to go
from an H1 to an H2 copy you know just
yeah yeah
[Music]
normally that would take quite a bit of
time to reset up a holography table to
make the transfer yeah of course of
course you know the major I think
features the system is uh
Malaysia for Mustang and for coping the
stuff that
it costs less yeah and second we have
the same wavelengths for recording then
for image planing
and the third that we use of laser for
both yeah and you imagine the vibration
isolation
requirements for especially for large
format holography that's really a
problem you know if you go for format
watches them at the most certain
Barefoot it becomes
really complicated so
this you know all those techniques they
actually work well anything else you'd
like to add to the show before we close
it out
if
a friend his photographer
from Moscow and basically this is his
invention I'm not really a legend but he
found this trick with a specification
for the material
um what else and maybe I would say
hello to a beautiful woman he's the
director of Micron plant
actually he's a producer of power effect
materials and he's good friend of mine
okay so yeah everybody can listen to
this show because it's on the internet
all right well thank you very much
Mikhail for uh coming on the show and
telling us about the new laser system
tell Rob I said thank you and good luck
with everything and thank you I'm sure
everybody will be interested in going to
your website for giola and also Rob's
website yeah thank you for your interest
okay take care thank you
thank you
foreign